evidencebasedteaching.org.au 2019-12-07

# Privacy Policy - Evidence-Based Teaching

Last updated: 24 July 2019

I’m Shaun Killian and I operate the [Australian Society for Evidence-Based Teaching website](https://www.evidencebasedteaching.org.au/).

* * *

## Your Privacy In A Nutshell

 **I take your privacy seriously**. I don’t collect private information except to:

  * Improve the service I offer you
  * Comply with legal directives

The remainder of this page gives you more details about how I collect, use and disclose your personal information.

I will not use or share your information with anyone except as described in this Privacy Policy.

* * *

## All Website Visitors

### Cookies

Cookies are files with small amount of data, which may include an anonymous unique identifier. Cookies are sent to your browser from a web site and stored on your computer’s hard drive.

For example, I use cookies that prevent pop-up subscribe forms from showing, if you have already subscribed to my email list.

Advertisers, such as Google Adsense and Amazon may also use cookies on this site.

By using this website, you agree to the collection and use of information in accordance with this policy.

### Anonymous Statistics

I collect anonymous statistics, often through Google Analytics.

For example, I can use this information to help identify what is popular on the site. This allows me to tailor and improve what I share on the site.

* * *

## Readers Who Leave Comments

Some of our articles invite readers to leave comments. If you wish to leave a comment, you must provide a name and an email address. our name is publically available to anyone reading your comment. Your email address remains **private**.

If you:

  * Use an existing social media account to sign in, or
  * Have a Gravatar linked to your email address

Then, your profile picture will show beside your name.

* * *

## Readers Who Subscribe to My Email List

I encourage you to subscribe to my email list. If you do, you must supply your name and email address. You may also be asked to describe your role (e.g. teacher, school leader, other), and to name the organisation you work for. You can choose to unsubscribe from my email list at any time – simply click the ‘unsubscribe’ link at the bottom of every email I send you.

I use your name and email address to send you updates with my latest articles and offerings. I use information such as your role and the organisation you work for to gain a deeper understanding of my audience. Again, this allows me to tailor and improve what I offer you.

### Service Providers

I use **Aweber** to send updates to my email subscribers. Aweber is one of the leading email marketing services available. While Aweber stores your personal information, it does not share it with anyone other me, or people acting on my behalf – except to comply with a legal directive. You can read [Aweber’s Privacy Policy](https://www.aweber.com/privacy.htm) here.

I use **OptinMonster** to generate some of the subscription forms I use on this website. OptinMonster collects anonymous data – such as which form is most successful at enticing subscribers. It does not store any of your personal information.

I use other service providers to help me with the technical side of the website. These service providers have limited access to personal information, but they are bound not to share it.

* * *

## Security

The security of your personal information is important to us, but remember that no method of transmission over the Internet, or method of electronic storage is 100% secure. While I strive to use commercially acceptable means to protect your personal information, I cannot guarantee its absolute security.

* * *

## Links To Other Sites

My website contains links to other sites that are not operated by me. If you click on a third party link, you will be directed to that third party’s site. I have no control over and assume no responsibility for the content, policies or practices of third party sites.

* * *

## Children’s Privacy

Some school students may be interested in reading some of the material on this site, and they are welcome to do so.

I do not encourage or recommend students under the age of 18 to comment on articles or to subscribe to my email updates.

If you are a parent or guardian and you are aware that your child has provided me with personal information, please [contact me](https://www.evidencebasedteaching.org.au/contact-me/). If I discover that a child under 18 has provided us with personal information, I will delete such information from my servers and services immediately.

* * *

## Compliance With Laws

I will disclose your personal information when required to do so by law or subpoena.

* * *

## Changes To This Privacy Policy

I may update this Privacy Policy from time to time. Changes will appear on this page, along with the date of the last update.
